{
    "pest": {
        "HCI-Chapter_1": ["Human-Computer Interaction", "Human, Computer and Interaction", "Memex system", "Douglas Engelbert", "1962",
                         "Sketchpad", "Alto computer", "Macintosh computer", "World Wide Web", "iPhone", "Usability", "User Experience", "Accessibility", "Efficiency and Performance",
                         "Adaptability and Flexibility", "Safety and Reliability", "Ethical and Social Consideration", "Psychology", "Computer Science", "Design", "Human Factors and Ergonomics", "Cognitive Science", "Information Science", "Anthropology and Sociology", "Linguistics", "Ethnography",
                         "User-Friendly Design", "Avoiding Errors and Frustration", "Real-World Application", "Integration with the Design Process", "Legal and Safety Requirements"
                        ],
        "HCI-Chapter_2": ["Interaction", "Instructing", "Conversing", "Manipulating", "Exploring", "Responding", "Normans Seven Stages of Action", "Model", "Hassenzahl UX Model",
                        "Framework", "User Model", "Task Model", "Cognitive Model", "Interaction Model", "Word", "Visual Representation", "Physical objects or space",
                        "Time", "Behavior", "Significant", "Enjoyable", "Covenient", "Usable", "Fuctional", "Product Features", "Expercience", "Excitement", "Entry", "Engagement", "Exit", "Extension",
                        "Ergonomics", "Visibility", "Consistency", "Feedback", "Flexibility", "Constraints", "Mapping", "Affordance"
                        ]
    },

    "app": {

        "HCI-Chapter_1": [
            {
                "question": "It is the study of the interface between people(user) and computers.",
                "answer": "Human-Computer Interaction",
                "id": 1
            },

            {
                "question": "To design technology systems and interface that meet user's needs and provide positive and satisfying experience.",
                "answer": "Human-Computer Interaction",
                "id": 2
            },

            {
                "question": "What are the fundamental components of HCI?",
                "answer": "Human, Computer and Interaction",
                "id": 3
            },

            {
                "question": "in 1945 Vannever Bush describes a __________, which is a precursor to hypertext.",
                "answer": "Memex system",
                "id": 4
            },

            {
                "question": "Who invented the mouse?",
                "answer": "Douglas Engelbert",
                "id": 5
            },

            {
                "question": "When Douglas Engelbert intoduce the mouse?",
                "answer": "1962",
                "id": 6
            },

            {
                "question": "In 1968 Ivan Sutherland develops __________, one of the first graphical interface",
                "answer": "Sketchpad",
                "id": 7
            },

            {
                "question": "Xerox PARC develops the __________, which features a graphical user interface similar to the Macintosh.",
                "answer": "Alto computer",
                "id": 8
            },

            {
                "question": "In 1984 the __________ is realeased, popularizing the use of graphical user interface",
                "answer": "Macintosh computer",
                "id": 10
            },

            {
                "question": "In 1993 the __________ is created, which makes it possible for people to interact with computers over the internet.",
                "answer": "World Wide Web",
                "id": 11
            },

            {
                "question": "In 2007 the __________ was released, which populized the use of touchscreens for HCI.",
                "answer": "iPhone",
                "id": 12
            },

            {
                "question": "The first augmented reality (Ar) headset was __________, which opened up new possibilities for HCI.",
                "answer": "Google Glass",
                "id": 13
            },

            {
                "question": "The goal is to create interfaces and interactions that are intuitive, efficient, and enjoyable for users, ultimately leading to a positive user experience and increased user satisfaction.",
                "answer": "Usability",
                "id": 14
            },

            {
                "question": "Refers to the overall experience and perception that a user has when interacting with a computer system, software application, website, or any digital product.",
                "answer": "User Experience",
                "id": 15
            },

            {
                "question": "Refers to the design and implementation of digital products, software applications, websites, and other technology interfaces in a way that ensures equal access and usability for individuals with disabilities.",
                "answer": "Accessibility",
                "id": 16
            },

            {
                "question": "These are essential aspects of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) that focus on how well a system or interface performs and how efficiently users can accomplish their tasks",
                "answer": "Efficiency and Performance",
                "id": 17
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ are critical aspects of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) that focus on ensuring that technology interfaces and systems are dependable, secure, and free from errors that could lead to harm or undesirable consequences for users.",
                "answer": "Safety and Reliability",
                "id": 18
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ are important concepts in Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) that focus on designing interfaces and systems that can accommodate a wide range of user needs, preferences, and changing conditions",
                "answer": "Adaptability and Flexibility",
                "id": 19
            },

            {
                "question": "HCI professionals and designers must be mindful of the ethical implications and broader societal impacts of their work.",
                "answer": "Ethical and Social Consideration",
                "id": 20
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ helps HCI professionals better understand and design technology interfaces that are more effective, user-friendly, and tailored to human cognitive and emotional processes.",
                "answer": "Psychology",
                "id": 21
            },

            {
                "question": "This  collaborate closely with HCI designers, psychologists, and other professionals to create technology interfaces that are not only technically sound but also user-centered and aligned with human needs and behavior.",
                "answer": "Computer Science",
                "id": 22
            },

            {
                "question": "It involves the planning, creation, and optimization of technology interfaces to ensure that they are user-friendly, visually appealing, and effective in facilitating user interactions.",
                "answer": "Design",
                "id": 23
            },

            {
                "question": "It focuses on optimizing the design of technology interfaces, systems, and physical environments to enhance human performance, safety, and well-being.",
                "answer": "Human Factors and Ergonomics",
                "id": 24
            },

            {
                "question": "Understanding how humans think, perceive, learn, and make decisions is essential for designing user-friendly and effective technology interfaces.",
                "answer": "Cognitive Science",
                "id": 25
            },

            {
                "question": "It focusing on the organization, retrieval, and use of information within technology interfaces. HCI professionals often draw from Information Science principles to create interfaces that facilitate efficient information access and management.",
                "answer": "Information Science",
                "id": 26
            },

            {
                "question": "Understanding human behavior, social interactions, and cultural norms is essential for designing technology interfaces and systems that align with the needs and values of diverse user populations.",
                "answer": "Anthropology and Sociology",
                "id": 27
            },

            {
                "question": "It focusing on the study of language and communication, which are essential components of human-computer interactions. Understanding linguistic principles is crucial for designing technology interfaces that facilitate effective communication between users and machines.",
                "answer": "Linguistics",
                "id": 28
            },

            {
                "question": "Helps HCI professionals gain a deep understanding of users' behaviors, needs, and cultural contexts.",
                "answer": "Ethnography",
                "id": 29
            },

            {
                "question": "HCI professionals create technology interfaces and systems that are not only functional but also enjoyable, efficient, and accessible to a wide range of users, ultimately leading to a positive and user-friendly experience.",
                "answer": "User-Friendly Design",
                "id": 30
            },

            {
                "question": " User-friendly interfaces should be designed to minimize the occurrence of errors and help users recover from them smoothly",
                "answer": "Avoiding Errors and Frustration",
                "id": 31
            },

            {
                "question": "HCI professionals and researchers continue to innovate and adapt principles to address emerging technologies and changing user needs in these and other domains, making technology more accessible, usable, and enjoyable for users.",
                "answer": "Real-World Application",
                "id": 32
            },

            {
                "question": "By integrating HCI throughout the design process, designers and developers can create technology interfaces and systems that prioritize user needs, are intuitive and accessible, and ultimately provide a positive and effective user experience. This iterative and user-centered approach contributes to the success of the product in the real world.",
                "answer": "Integration with the Design Process",
                "id": 33
            },

            {
                "question": "Designing and developing technology interfaces and systems. Compliance with relevant laws and safety standards is essential to protect users, ensure ethical practices, and avoid legal consequences.",
                "answer": "Legal and Safety Requirements",
                "id": 34
            }
        ],

        "HCI-Chapter_2": [
            {
                "question": "Refers to the dynamic exchange of information and actions between a user and a computer or digital system.",
                "answer": "Interaction",
                "id": 35
            },

            {
                "question": "Users provide explicit commands or instructions to a computer system to perform specific actions",
                "answer": "Instructing",
                "id": 37
            },

            {
                "question": "Expecting response from the computer",
                "answer": "Conversing",
                "id": 38
            },

            {
                "question": "Cotrolling software applications",
                "answer": "Manipulating",
                "id": 39
            },

            {
                "question": "Navigating or discovering the system or application.",
                "answer": "Exploring",
                "id": 40
            },

            {
                "question": "Responding of a computer to the user and vice versa.",
                "answer": "Responding",
                "id": 41
            },

            {
                "question": "This model is widely used in the field of Human-Computer Interaction (HCI) and user experience (UX) design to understand how users interact with systems and how design can influence the user experience.",
                "answer": "Normans Seven Stages of Action",
                "id": 42
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ is a framework used to understand and evaluate the user experience (UX) in interactive products and systems. This model emphasizes that the user experience goes beyond usability and functionality, considering the emotional and hedonic aspects of user interactions.",
                "answer": "Hassenzahl UX Model",
                "id": 43
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ help to describe and explain various facets of human-computer interaction.",
                "answer": "Model",
                "id": 44
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ in HCI provides a structured approach, set of principles, or guidelines for designing, evaluating, or analyzing aspects of human-computer interaction.",
                "answer": "Framework",
                "id": 45
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ represent the characteristics, behaviors, and needs of the users who interact with a computer system. They are used to design interfaces that match the user's mental model and expectations.",
                "answer": "User Model",
                "id": 46
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ delve into the mental processes and cognitive aspects involved in human-computer interaction. They aim to understand how users think, perceive, learn, and make decisions when using computer systems",
                "answer": "Cognitive Model",
                "id": 47
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ describe the sequence of actions and steps that users take to complete specific tasks or goals using a computer system. These models help designers create interfaces that support efficient task execution",
                "answer": "Task Model",
                "id": 48
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ illustrate the patterns and sequences of user actions and system responses during interaction. They are used to design interfaces that facilitate smooth and effective user-system communication.",
                "answer": "Interaction Model",
                "id": 49
            },

            {
                "question": "What does 1D means in Five Dimensions of Interaction Design",
                "answer": "Word",
                "id": 50
            },

            {
                "question": "What does 2D means in Five Dimensions of Interaction Design",
                "answer": "Visual Representation",
                "id": 51
            },

            {
                "question": "What does 3D means in Five Dimensions of Interaction Design",
                "answer": "Physical objects or space",
                "id": 52
            },

            {
                "question": "What does 4D means in Five Dimensions of Interaction Design",
                "answer": "Time",
                "id": 53
            },

            {
                "question": "What does 5D means in Five Dimensions of Interaction Design",
                "answer": "Behavior",
                "id": 54
            },

            {
                "question": "in this level in UX design pyramid, the application is working.",
                "answer": "Functional",
                "id": 55
            },

            {
                "question": "in this level in UX design pyramid, you are using the app to accomplish a task.",
                "answer": "Usable",
                "id": 56
            },

            {
                "question": "in this level in UX design pyramid, you are now using the app more than you need.",
                "answer": "Convenient",
                "id": 57
            },

            {
                "question": "in this level in UX design pyramid, you are now relying on this app.",
                "answer": "Enjoyable",
                "id": 58
            },

            {
                "question": "in this level in UX design pyramid, you can't live without this app.",
                "answer": "Significant",
                "id": 59
            },

            {
                "question": "The one whom computer systems are designed to assist.",
                "answer": "Human",
                "id": 60
            },

            {
                "question": "It a type of memory that stores information from the senses for a very short period of time.",
                "answer": "Sensory Memory",
                "id": 61
            },

            {
                "question": "In this phase in 5E Experience Design Model, the application is now deployed",
                "answer": "Entry",
                "id": 62
            },

            {
                "question": "In this phase in 5E Experience Design Model, the team will organizing events and other strategies to keep users using the app",
                "answer": "Engagement",
                "id": 63
            },

            {
                "question": "This the fourth phase in 5E Experience Design Model",
                "answer": "Exit",
                "id": 64
            },

            {
                "question": "In this phase in 5E Experience Design Model, the application has a extra features to keep the user using their app. ex. notifications, event, daily rewards.",
                "answer": "Extension",
                "id": 65
            },

            {
                "question": "In this phase in 5E Experience Design Model, the team is makig a promotional events like advertisement before deploying the app",
                "answer": "Excitement",
                "id": 66
            },

            {
                "question": "__________, also known as human factors engineering, aims to create systems and environments that are comfortable, efficient, safe, and conducive to human well-being during computer use.",
                "answer": "Ergonomics",
                "id": 67
            },

            {
                "question": "It is the basic principle that the more visible an element is, the more likely user will know about them and how to use them.",
                "answer": "Visibility",
                "id": 68
            },

            {
                "question": "It is the principle of making it clear to the user what action has been taken and what has been accomplished.",
                "answer": "Feedback",
                "id": 69
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ is a about limiting the range of iteraction possibilities for the user to simplify the interface and guide the user to appropriate next action.",
                "answer": "Constraints",
                "id": 70
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ refers to having similar operations and similar elements for achieving similar tasks.",
                "answer": "Consistency",
                "id": 71
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ is about having a clear realationship between controls and the effect they have on the world.",
                "answer": "Mapping",
                "id": 72
            },

            {
                "question": "Refers to the attribute of the objects that allows people to know how to use it",
                "answer": "Affordance",
                "id": 73
            },
            {
                "question": "The first step of how our memory stores information.",
                "answer": "Sensory memories",
                "id": 74
            },

            {
                "question": "This action is needed to store the sensory into Short-term memory or working memory.",
                "answer": "Attention",
                "id": 75
            },

            {
                "question": "When you give an attentention into information, that information will now store in to?",
                "answer": "Short-term memory",
                "id": 76
            },

            {
                "question": "We need this so we can store this information in to long-term memory",
                "answer": "Rehearsal",
                "id": 77
            },

            {
                "question": "It is a temporary storage system that holds information that is currently being used.",
                "answer": "Short-term memory",
                "id": 78
            },

            {
                "question": "It is the inability to acces information from our memory.",
                "answer": "Forgetting",
                "id": 79
            },

            {
                "question": "It is what we called when we accessing information from our memory",
                "answer": "Retrieval",
                "id": 80
            },

            {
                "question": "You are storing or putting information to your memory",
                "answer": "Storing",
                "id": 81
            },

            {
                "question": "Using knowledge to draw conclusion or infer new information",
                "answer": "Reasoning",
                "id": 82
            },

            {
                "question": "Derives a logically necessary conclusion from given premises, even if it doesn't always align with our notion of truth.",
                "answer": "Deductive",
                "id": 83
            },

            {
                "question": "Generalized from observed cases to infer information about unobserved cases, although it may not be entirely reilable.",
                "answer": "Inductive",
                "id": 84
            },

            {
                "question": "Reasons from a fact to the cause of the fact, helping us derive explanations for observed events",
                "answer": "Abductive",
                "id": 85
            },

            {
                "question": "It is process of finding a solution to an unfamiliar task using the knowledge we have.",
                "answer": "Problem-solving",
                "id": 86
            },

            {
                "question": "In this theory, you are deviding or restructuring the problem and gaining insight to find innovattive solutions.",
                "answer": "Gestalt theory",
                "id": 87
            },

            {
                "question": "We called it a trial and error theory.",
                "answer": "Problem space theory",
                "id": 88
            },

            {
                "question": "Refers to the process of gaining experties and proficiency in a particular domain over time. It is a complex process that involves a number of factors.",
                "answer": "Skill acquisition",
                "id": 89
            },

            {
                "question": "It is a factor in skill acquisition that said, you are gaining skill through teaching",
                "answer": "Transfer",
                "id": 90
            },

            {
                "question": "__________ are unintentional actions that devirate from the desired outcome. They can range from minor inconveniences to serious consequences.",
                "answer": "Errors",
                "id": 91
            },

            {
                "question": "This component represents how humans gather information from the environment. It involves sensory processes such as vision, hearing, touch, and other senses.",
                "answer": "Perceptual system",
                "id": 92
            },

            {
                "question": "It is responsible for executing physical actions in response to the information processed by the cognitive system.",
                "answer": "motor system",
                "id": 93
            },

            {
                "question": "It is responsible for tasks such as memory, attention, problem-solving, decision-making, and language processing. It processes the information received from the perceptual system and generates actions based on that information.",
                "answer": "cognitive system",
                "id": 94
            },

            {
                "question": "refers to the sensory memory associated with visual information. It is extremely short-lived, lasting only for a fraction of a second (typically less than a second).",
                "answer": "iconic memory",
                "id": 95
            },

            {
                "question": "the sensory memory associated with auditory information, such as sounds and spoken language. It lasts longer than iconic memory, typically around 2 to 4 seconds",
                "answer": "Echoic Memory",
                "id": 96
            },

            {
                "question": "This sensory information helps you recognize objects, navigate your environment, and perform various tactile tasks.",
                "answer": "Haptic Memory",
                "id": 97
            },

            {
                "question": "efers to the system responsible for encoding, storing, and retrieving personal experiences and specific events or episodes in your life",
                "answer": "Episodic Memory",
                "id": 98
            },
            
            {
                "question": " It involves the storage of factual knowledge, concepts, and information that are not tied to specific personal experiences. This type of memory encompasses a wide range of information, such as facts, concepts, language, and general knowledge about the world.",
                "answer": "Semantic Memory",
                "id": 99
            }
        ]
    }
}
